adjustable dumbbells can be a complete
Lifesaver for a ton of people they're
going to save you space as opposed to
having a full set of traditional
dumbbells in your home gym but they're
also going to save you a chunk of change
at the same time now similar with all
other fitness equipment everybody wants
to know which one is the absolute best
well I've got two options right here in
front of me that I definitely think
contend for that number one spot we've
got the snowed adjustable dumbbells and
we got the ever popular nuo Bells both
of these dumbbells are beasts the
adjustment process is super quick and
easy but is one better than the other
stick around and we'll find out
[Music]
[Applause]
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym and this time around
we're going to be comparing two of the
hottest adjustable dumbbells that are on
the market yep that's right we got the
Snows and we got the nuo bills there's a
lot to like about both of these
dumbbells individually but we're gonna
take some time like I said compare both
of them we're gonna talk about actual
size we're going to talk about some
materials we're gonna talk about the
adjustment process we're going to talk
about some money but most importantly
we're going to talk about you know which
one is best for you specifically now
before I do all of that gotta let you
guys know we've reviewed a ton of
adjustable dumbbells on barbin.com and
we went ahead and made a best list you
don't have to do all that hard work
yourself all you gotta do is search bar
Ben best adjustable dumbbells that list
is going to pull right up for you you
can find out for yourself which ones we
like the best who knows you might be
surprised which one cracks that number
one spot
foreign
so let's go ahead and talk about you
know actual Aesthetics with both of
these adjustable dumbbells they look
identical you know at first glance but
they're they're not a promise all right
so the snodes measure 18 and a half
inches long while the newer builds are
17 inches so they're more compact
obviously the same goes with the handles
all right so the handles on the Snows
actually you know an inch and a half or
an inch I guess longer than the nuo
bells so you know that center of gravity
you know the compactness being you know
closer to your hand the center of
gravity and everything it could be you
know a crucial thing for some people
some people might not care about it but
it's definitely worth noting that now
sticking with the handles right here
you know with the Snows they're actually
thicker than with the newer Bells so
these are 36 millimeters in diameter
while with the newer Bells they're 28
millimeters you can definitely tell a
difference once you get your hands on
both of them I personally like the
thicker handles on the Snows just kind
of gives me more to grip and you know so
that might be you know something that
you want as well so definitely you know
give the nod to the Snows in that regard
but overall I kind of like how compact
the nuo bells are it just kind of you
know feels more like you know a
traditional dumbbell which is pretty
cool
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the materials
used for both of these dumbbells and
kind of the durability you can expect
out of both of them all right so let's
talk about the cradles first and this
isn't you know impacting your actual
workouts by any means but it does affect
you know when you go to store your
dumbbells all right so with the newer
bills this cradle is in fact made of
plastic with aluminum rods well with the
Snows this is all cast iron and you know
this is this is Chrome plated right here
I honestly I love this this is you know
pretty unique it's pretty rare and you
just don't you don't have to be as
careful whenever you go to you know set
your dumbbells back in their home after
you know a grueling you know workout
session or a set or whatever and it's
something you definitely got to do with
the new ability so definitely you know
just just keep that in mind now as far
as the actual plates go the weight
plates with the Snows these are cast
iron and with the new Bells these are
steel now I don't think one is going to
be more durable than the other I think
they're both going to hold up just fine
in the long run and you know that's just
personal preference I guess now with the
newer battles you you have plastic that
kind of connects each dumbbell head the
weight plates excuse me together right
here and with the Snows there's nothing
you know it's all just cast orange I
honestly just I think it's kind of cool
so now with the handles both of them are
fully knurled and they're straight
across I like that I personally don't
like ergonomically shaped handles where
the middle is is thicker than the ends
so being able to just kind of grab and
go is just a nice thing to me personally
and the knurling overall they're about
the same honestly I don't think one is
better than the other they're both you
know moderately passive I guess not so
smooth where you can't get a good grip
they're honestly they get the job done
now both of them are Chrome plated right
here and whenever you adjust the weight
there's an aluminum rod that you know
attaches to the weight plates and that's
kind of how you know they pull them out
now overall the new Bells have more
plastic but I don't think they're
necessarily less durable than the Snows
which is kind of you know the whole
selling point with these you know
they're rated to be dropped from 32
inches now I personally haven't done
that I don't really want to do that I
don't I'm not the kind of person who you
know works out and just drops or
dumbbells anyways
so I haven't done that but you know I've
had the new Abels for well over a year
now I haven't had any issues in terms of
durability they look almost brand new to
be completely honest with you something
with the Snows that I haven't been too
excited about to find is first of all I
haven't had these that long and like I
said I don't drop my dumbbells but
there's a crack right here in this cast
iron and that's certainly you know not
something that you want to find so it
definitely happened during Transit which
also is kind of alarming to me but
that's just something worth noting you
know like if it was with it's like that
with with me it might happen with you
now as I mentioned you know there's more
plastic so right here on the handle you
know these are these this is plastic
right here now only thing you gotta
worry about I think in terms of you know
durability is this plate that's
connected right here that being the
thing that cracks whenever you drop
these you know recklessly so keep that
in mind and I just talked about it the
adjustment process and I want to expand
on that now so with the newer bells to
adjust the weight all you do is just sit
here and turn this handle it's like
you're revving up a motorcycle or
something you know and I like that you
can fly through the the increments
really fast so you have five pound
increments with the new abilities that's
something that I think is really cool
you know with adjustable dumbbells with
any any Dumbo really a lot of the
exercises you're doing you know
shoulder press you know lateral raise
front raise fill in the blank even curls
and tricep extensions you don't
necessarily want to jump up you know in
a bunch of weight really fast so I think
it's something where the snow is kind of
you know fall behind to the newer bills
that's because you know from 10 to 80
pounds
you only have 10 pound increments right
so once again you have five to eighty
with the newer bills 10 to 80 with the
Snows unless you go and purchase their
magnetic weights which you know pop on
the side right here and you've got eight
of them each one weighs 1.25 pounds you
could make the argument that is superior
to Five Pound increments I think that's
kind of cool I don't have any right now
obviously but I think it's kind of cool
you know certain exercises as I was just
mentioning you can kind of jump up one
1.25 two and a half pounds whatever it
is and that's nice you can really expand
that way so to adjust these dumbbells
all you do is Twist this right here this
is pretty much the only plastic and it's
all centralized right here can't
remember if I just said that a second
ago doing a lot of talking right now and
it's really easy to adjust as well and
you just do that and you're good to go
overall though I think that this is a
little bit faster you know you just
adjust it and your hands are there and
pull it out but you know that micro you
know second might not be that big of a
deal for everybody
foreign
[Music]
touch on price you know just really
quick and you know full disclosure these
are the most both of these are the most
expensive adjustable dumbbells that are
available all right so they're both
going to run you right around 800 bucks
you know at that base price tag but if
you go all in so go all in this nodes
are going to be more expensive when I
say all in you're going for you know
with these specifically the magnetic
weights and the optional stand and then
with newer Bells it's just the stand
these are gonna be about 40 bucks more
expensive that's because of those
magnetic weights they're right around
forty dollars now
you know pricing like I said they're
basically identical so it's not like you
know one of them is worth going after
because of they're cheaper or anything
like that really this shouldn't even
factor in that much because you're
already spending more on these than you
will on any other adjustable dumbbell
that is available so definitely keep
that in mind at the end of the day you
know you're getting what you pay for you
know these are both of these are really
durable Gonna Last you a long time
they're heavy you know like I said 80
pounds a piece you know you're going to
be able to grow with them they're going
to be able to meet the needs of the
majority of athletes so yeah pricing it
is what it is they're expensive might
not be too crazy about it but I think
they fit the bill
foreign
so as I like to do I like pulling you up
nice close and personal and kind of
reiterating some things and just showing
you up close so let's talk about the
adjustment process remember you know
with the snodes you just twist this
little mechanism right here and you're
able to fly through all of your weights
so you have a little window right there
it's going to show you you know what
everything weighs that way you know what
you're lifting now with the Snows
remember it's
Twist of the handle right here I like
that it's louder but you know it's a
little bit quicker in the long run just
because your hand's already here you can
just adjust the weight and then pull it
out of the cradle and you're good to go
so speaking of pulling them out of the
Cradle let's do that as you can see you
got a little bit more room on either
side with the Snows as opposed to with
the newer bills I personally you know
don't think it matters but you do
technically have you know center of
gravity being closer to your hand yada
yada so people might like that better
just kind of keep that in mind now you
can see you know there's really no
plastic here other than this adjustment
piece but there is good amount of
plastic right here with the new bill so
you would think that they would be less
durable
they're really not you know like I said
I've had these for over a year and
there's really no signs of wear and tear
yet
I have not had these for anywhere close
to a year yet and there's already a
crack right here on that cast iron which
is not ideal it's less than ideal so I
think it's still going to hold up fine
but that's kind of a bummer especially
considering you know how expensive both
of these dumbbells are right here so you
just kind of want to remember that now
let's talk about the actual weight
plates as I mentioned these are fully
cast iron these are steel and they have
a little bit of plastic right there to
you know Glide in between the plates I
don't see any wear and tear honestly I
don't see any wear and tear that's a
good sign I think that they're going to
hold up really well oh but I do like how
they're flat right here and now you can
do push-ups on the ground with the new
bills you can't do that with the Snows
because as you see it's rounded that's
perfectly rounded you know they're not
going to hold up and really you know
stay flat on the ground for you I do
though I do like how this is all cast
iron I don't like I don't necessarily
like how the plastic is right here so I
like that a lot right there but one
thing that new Abel has got going on
compared to the Snows is these little
weights right here so there's two of
them two and a half pounds and that's
how you're getting those 15 25 35 pound
you know weight options as opposed to
you know forcing you know being forced
should I say to get those magnetic
weights that go on the ends right here
and you got to deal with you know
attaching them taking them off and all
that stuff so that's something I just
think new Abel has got going on
[Music]
okay so let's do the hard part now and
decide you know which one is the best
hate to break it to you though honestly
you can't go wrong with either one of
these dumbbells you know they're heavy
they're easy to adjust and they're
durable you know they're made of durable
materials but there are a few questions
you need to ask yourself to help you
determine which one is best for you
specifically you know do you want you
know the micro transactions with the
magnetic weights but you know you have
to pay extra for that so do you want to
skip out on that and just have the five
pound increments you know mixed in with
the newer Bells do you want to skip out
on this plastic you want to go for this
cast iron build right here there's you
know a lot of factors that go in right
here now me personally I think I still
got to give the nod to the newer bills
you know I personally like the more
compact design I like having those five
pound increments I like how I don't have
to worry about you know keeping up with
eight different magnetic weights and
then what if I'm working out and somehow
I mean it really shouldn't because it's
a magnet but what if it falls and hits
me in the face that's not going to be
fun it's not gonna be not going to feel
good so like I said me personally
you know I think I got to go with the
newer bills but honestly y'all you know
the snow's really made this a tough
decision to me and I definitely
understand why these are so highly
touted you know because of all the
things that I just mentioned
[Music]
foreign
wrap on today's comparison between the
nuo bills and the Snows these are you
know like I said two of the most popular
adjustable dumbbells on the market and
they certainly pass the test with flying
colors they're both really heavy you
know 80 pounds apiece there's also a 50
pound pair that both companies offer not
want to check those out
they're really easy to adjust the weight
and they're super durable but they both
have their pros and cons either one of
them is absolutely perfect so you're
gonna have to you know weigh those
options and really decide for yourself
which one suits your needs absolute best
thanks for watching y'all I hope this
video was really helpful and I was able
to answer everything you need to know
about both of these adjustable dumbbells
as always stay posted for the next video
but for now head over to barbin.com so
we have a full written comparison
article about these adjustable dumbbells
all you gotta do is search bar band
snowed versus new about adjustable
dumbbell review it's going to pull right
up for you you can go over everything we
talked about here today I'll catch y'all
next time
[Music]
friends
foreign
[Music]